Guide to the Civic Club of Allegheny County Records, 1896-1974 AIS.1970.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- The Exceptionally Able Youth Program, 1916-1973; VII.
  - Programs, general, 1.
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Awardees Reunion Lists and RSVPs, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Club, 1930-1931 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - List of Exceptionally Able Youths Test Takers and Awardees, 1930-1937 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Studies Regarding Exceptionally Able Youth Program's Success, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1930-1931 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Press Releases Regarding Tests and Awards, 1930, 1947-1956 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Allegheny County Joint Committee on Scholarship Aid, 1932-1951 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1932-1934 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Letters to Principals Regarding Exceptionally Able Youths, 1932-1971 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Letters to Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees, 1933-1940 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Report to Phi Beta Kappa Scholarship Promotion Committee, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1935-1938 (Box 34, Folder 23-24)
    - Sample Exceptionally Able Youths Certificates, 1938-1942 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Friends of Youth, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 26-27)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 28-29)
    - Awardees Lists, 1939-1967 (Box 34, Folder 30)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Meetings, 1940-1947 (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Correspondence, 1940-1968 (Box 34, Folder 32)
    - Lists of Scholarship Applicants, 1940-1943 (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - Letters to Newspapers, 1940-1946 (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Test Takers, 1940-1947, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 34, Folder 36-37)
    - "Studies of Exceptionally Able Youth Program Effectiveness" by David Henderson, undated (Box 34, Folder 38)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Clippings, 1942-1945 (Box 34, Folder 39-40)
    - Correspondence and Test, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 41)
    - Memos Regarding Exceptionally Able Youth Program, 1943-1946, 1950-1953 (Box 34, Folder 42)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Nominee Lists, 1943-1946, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 43)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Committee Meeting Minutes, 1946-1953 (Box 34, Folder 44)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Clippings, 1946-1953 (Box 34, Folder 45-48)
    - Student Information Sheets, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence Regarding Exceptionally Able Youths Testing, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 50)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Semi-Annual Test Announcements, 1947-1956 (Box 34, Folder 51)
    - This Week in Pittsburgh Exceptionally Able Youths Announcements, 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 52)
    - Vocational Opportunities Division of Exceptionally Able Youths, 1948-1951 (Box 34, Folder 53-54)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Committee Awardees Meeting, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 55)
    - "The Social Status and Vertical Social Mobility of a Selected Group of High School Graduates" Bound Thesis by David Henderson, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 56)
    - General Scholarship Information, 1950-1959 (Box 34, Folder 57)
    - Survey of Principals Regarding Date Change of Tests, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 58)
    - Miscellaneous Exceptionally Able Youths Letters, 1951-1954 (Box 34, Folder 59)
    - List of Exceptionally Able Youth Test Takers Requesting Placement, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 60)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Meeting, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 61)
    - Vocational Opportunities Division Applications A-Z, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 62-64)
    - "A Study of Exceptionally Able Youth in Allegheny County: 1916-1953" by Paul H. Masoner (Box 34, Folder 65)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Meetings, 1953-1954 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Regarding Exceptionally Able Youths Students and Procedure, 1954-1959 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "A Scholarship Program for Exceptionally Able Youth" Report by Paul H. Masoner, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Clippings, 1954-1973 (Box 35, Folder 04-07)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Committee Minutes and Agendas, 1954-1958 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Meetings and Testing, 1955-1956 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - "Survey of Vocational Plans and Counseling Needs of Exceptionally Able Youths" and pamphlets, 1955, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny County Joint Committee on Scholarship Aid, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Meetings, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - List of Pittsburgh Schools, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Letters of Recommendation for past Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees, 1959-1973 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees Meeting and Rank List, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Requests for Exceptionally Able Youths Test Result Forwarding, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Program and Legislation, 1963-1964 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Programs, 1963-1973 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Letters to Awardees, 1966, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Requests for Financial Support, 1966-1970 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Development, 1966-1973 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence- Exceptionally Able Youths Committee, 1966-1972 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Award Presentation, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Committee Meeting Minutes, 1966-1973 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Scholarship Donors, 1967-1971 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Counselors Diner, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Expenses, 1967-1973 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence with Speakers of the Award Presentation, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Letters from Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees, 1967-1971 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - List of Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees and Career Counselors, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Alphabetized Student List, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Nominee Statistics, 1968-1969 (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Article about Exceptionally Able Youths by Barbara Lowe, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Expansion Prospectus and Votes, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence with Chatham Communications Regarding Exceptionally Able Youths Expansion, 1970-1971 (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Award Presentation, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Photos of Awards Ceremony, 1970-1971 (Box 35, Folder 38-39)
    - School Information, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 40)
    - Assessment of Exceptionally Able Youth Program, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 41)
    - Requests for Exceptionally Able Youths Support, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Exceptionally Able Youths Program, 2.
    - Junior and Senior Designee Program, 1972-1973; 2. (Box 35, Folder 43-44)
    - 1972 Nominee Applications
      Scope and Contents note
      This subseries includes a complete set of Exceptionally Able Youth nominee applications for 1972. The applications were filled out by students and their counselors or principals representing school districts from all over Allegheny County.
      - Allegheny Academy, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 45)
      - Allegheny High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 46)
      - Avalon High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 47)
      - Avonworth Senior High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 48)
      - Baldwin High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 49)
      - Bellevue High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 50)
      - Bethel Park Senior High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 51)
      - Bishop's Latin School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 52)
      - Braddock Senior High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 53)
      - Brentwood High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 54)
      - Canevin High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 55)
      - Carlynton High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 56)
      - Carrick High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 57)
      - Central Catholic, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 58)
      - Chartiers Valley Senior High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 59)
      - Cornell High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 60)
      - Deer Lakes High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 61)
      - Divin Providence Academy, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 62)
      - Duquesne Senior High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 63)
      - Edgewood, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 64)
      - Elizabeth Forward, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 65)
      - Elizabeth Seton High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 66)
      - Fifth Avenue High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 67)
      - Fontbone Academy, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 68)
      - Fox Chapel High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 69)
      - Gateway Senior High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 70)
      - Gladstone High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 71)
      - Hampton High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 72)
      - Hilltop Catholic, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 73)
      - Holy Ghost High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 74)
      - Holy Innocents High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 75)
      - Thomas Jefferson High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 76)
      - Keystone Oaks High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 77)
      - Langley Junior-Senior High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 78)
      - Lawrenceville Catholic High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 79)
      - Mon-Yough Catholic High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 80)
      - Montour High, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 81)
      - Moon Senior High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 82)
      - Mount Alvernia High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 83)
      - Mount Assisi Academy, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 84)
      - Mt. Lebanon High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 85)
      - North Allegheny Senior High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 86)
      - North Catholic High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 87)
      - North Hills High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 88)
      - David B. Oliver High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 89)
      - Our Lady of Mercy Academy, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 90)
      - Our Lady of the Sacred Heart High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 91)
      - Peabody High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 92)
      - Penn Hills Senior High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 93)
      - Perry High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 94)
      - Plum Senior High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 95)
      - Quaker Valley High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 96)
      - Riverview High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 97)
      - Sacred Heart High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 98)
      - Saint Basil High School, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 99)
      - Saint Benedict Academy, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Saint Joseph High School - Mount Oliver, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Schenley High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Scott High School (General Braddock Area), 1972 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Sewickley Academy Senior School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - South Allegheny High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - South Fayette Township Junior/Senior High, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - South High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - South Hills Catholic High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - South Hills High, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - South Park, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - South Side Catholic High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Springdale High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - St. Elizabeth High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - St. Francis Academy, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - St. Joseph High, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - St. Mary High, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - St. Mary of the Mount High, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - St. Paul Cathedral High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - St. Thomas District High school, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - Sto-Rox Senior High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - Swissvale Area Joint High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 22)
      - Taylor Alderdice High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 23)
      - Turtle Creek Area High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 24)
      - Upper St. Clair High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 25)
      - Ursuline Academy, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 26)
      - Vicentian High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 27)
      - West Mifflin North High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 28)
      - West Mifflin South High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 29)
      - Westinghouse High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 30)
      - Wilkinsburg Senior High School, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 31)
      - Letters Regarding Readers' Digest Article about Exceptionally Able Youths, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 32)
      - Exceptionally Able Youths Award Presentation, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 33)
      - Photos of Awards Ceremony, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 34)
      - Letters of Congratulations to Parents and Awardees, undated (Box 36, Folder 35)
      - Awardees Personal Statements, undated (Box 36, Folder 36)
      - Blank Student Personal Data Form, undated (Box 36, Folder 37)
      - "Program for Detecting Able Youth" by James Snoke", undated (Box 36, Folder 38)
      - "Psychological Counseling for High School and College Students", undated (Box 36, Folder 39)
      - "Study of the Social and Economic Progress of Exceptionally Able Youths after College", undated (Box 36, Folder 40)
      - Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees, 1938-1966 (Box 36, Folder 41-42)
- Research and Subject Files, 1913-1974; VIII.
  In order for the Civic Club to be well versed in the various concerns of Allegheny County, it was important that committee members find materials regarding all topics needed for study. Members often read of solutions to problems in other industrial cities and would then work to apply them to challenges in Pittsburgh. These topics were researched and reported on by committees to the Board of Directors and local and state government officials. This series mainly focuses on issues from the 1960s to the 1970s. Some of these topics include local government budget and structure; stadium construction; taxation; parking; housing; public baths; Pittsburgh public schools; economic development; and civil disturbances such as violence, drugs, and blatant sexuality of which rock and roll was seen as a catalyst.
  Included are clippings, correspondence, reports, articles and pamphlets concerning these topics and more of Allegheny County's most pressing social and political issues mainly of the 1960s and 1970s. Most of the documents found in these records are research materials; however, some interesting inclusions are the leases for Three Rivers Stadium to the Pittsburgh Steelers and the Pittsburgh Pirates and photographs of Pittsburgh's courthouses.
  - Allegheny Regional Planning Council Newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 43)
  - Americans for Constitutional Action, 1967-1970 (Box 36, Folder 44)
  - Another Side Correspondence and Newsletters, 1967-1973 (Box 36, Folder 45)
  - Anti-Drug Correspondence and Pamphlets, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 46)
  - Anti-Violence Documents, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 47)
  - The Associated Charities of Pittsburgh Constitution and Board List, undated (Box 36, Folder 48)
  - Bidwell Cultural Center, undated (Box 36, Folder 49)
  - City Budget and Finance Clippings and Report, 1962-1973 (Box 36, Folder 50)
  - City Budget and Finance Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 36, Folder 51)
  - City Budget Correspondence and Transcripts, 1971-1974 (Box 36, Folder 52)
  - Civic Searchlight Pamphlet and Letter, undated (Box 36, Folder 53)
  - Civil Disturbance Clippings, 1963-1969 (Box 36, Folder 54)
  - Civil Disturbance Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 36, Folder 55)
  - Civil Disturbance Reports "Toward Reducing Crime in Pennsylvania" Volume 1 and 2, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 56)
  - Civil Rights and Black Studies Programs, 1968-1970 (Box 36, Folder 57)
  - Commonwealth Compensation Commission, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 58)
  - Constitutional Convention Preparation, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 59-60)
  - "Constitutions: Contracts for Survival" Seminars, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 61)
  - Coroner Wecht Correspondence and Testimony, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence Regarding County Government, 1922, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 63)
  - County Budget Reports, 1954-1972 (Box 36, Folder 64-65)
  - County Budget and Finance Clippings, 1967-1973 (Box 36, Folder 66-67)
  - County Industrial Development Authority Budget Clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 36, Folder 68)
  - County Jail Clippings, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 69)
  - County Report "1958-1965: Eight Year Capital Improvement Program for the County of Allegheny" (Box 36, Folder 70)
  - Courthouse Photos, undated (Box 36, Folder 71)
  - Courts and Judgeships Correspondence, 1963-1974 (Box 36, Folder 72)
  - Education Clippings, 1963, 1971-1974 (Box 36, Folder 73)
  - Federal Eminent Domain and Post Office Location, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 74)
  - "Financing Municipal Government: Recent Trends and a Proposal" by Stephen F. Gates, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 75)
  - Government Reorganization in Allegheny County, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 76)
  - Government Study Commission City of Pittsburgh Correspondence and Articles, 1970-1973 (Box 36, Folder 77)
  - Great High Schools Correspondence and Articles, 1967-1972 (Box 36, Folder 78)
  - High School Violence Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 79)
  - Home Exchange Plan, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 80)
  - Housing Authority Correspondence, Willie Lewis Complaints and Dismissal, 1966-1969 (Box 36, Folder 81)
  - Housing Authority Reports and Minutes, 1968-1971 (Box 36, Folder 82)
  - Housing Authority Correspondence, Clippings and Reports, 1970-1973 (Box 37, Folder 01-02)
  - International Economics and Development Praeger Series, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - John J. Kane Hospital and MDC Systems, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 04-06)
  - Juvenile Detention Home, 1970-1972 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Lake Erie/Ohio River Canal Correspondence and Fact Book, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Law and Government Center Site Reports, Correspondence and Clippings, 1956-1974 (Box 37, Folder 09-12)
  - Malie Bill Clippings, 1913 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda and Bill Studies, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 14-15)
  - Mildred Benson Correspondence Regarding Mental Health Act of 1967 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Milk Board Legislation, Correspondence and Reports, 1965-1973 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Mon Plaza and Convention Center Proposal, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Movement Against Sex and Drug Revolution, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity and Rittle Demonstration, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Pamphlets Regarding Plans for Pittsburgh, undated (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Parking Authority Clippings and Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania City Government Chart and Political Booklets, 1917, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Pennsylvania Economy League Newsletter, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Peoples Baths on Penn Avenue Specifications, undated (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - "People's Bond Program for Capital Improvements", 1965 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Pittsburgh Free University, 1967-1969 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Pittsburgh Model Cities Program Reports and Clippings, 1970-1972 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Pittsburgh Schools Article "Digest of Reports on Various Phases and Activities of the Pittsburgh Public Schools", 1933 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Pittsburgh School Budgets and Finance Correspondence and Reports, 1918, 1969-1972 (Box 37, Folder 30-32)
  - Pittsburgh Service Organizations and Businesses List, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Political Revolution Documents, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Property Assessment Reports, Clippings and Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 37, Folder 35-37)
  - Property Tax Administration and Exemptions Presentations, 1970-1971 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Property Assessment Law Report and Draft, 1970-1971 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Public Employee Relations Clippings and Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - Renaming of Centre Avenue Correspondence, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Right to Work Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1969-1972 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Senator Frank Mazzei Scandal, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - Soho Bath Construction, 1906 (Box 37, Folder 44-45)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission Report, 1972-1974 (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Squirrel Hill Library and Parking Area Reports and Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Stadium and Arena Clippings and Ordinances, 1956-1969 (Box 37, Folder 48-50)
  - Stadium Reports and Articles, 1965-1971 (Box 38, Folder 01-02)
  - Stadium Authority Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 38, Folder 03-04)
  - Citizens Regarding Stadium Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Three Rivers Stadium Basic Agreement, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Lease and Sublease Agreements of Three Rivers Stadium, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 07-08)
  - Stadiums in Other Cities Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Stadium Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - State Budget and Finance Clippings, Correspondence and Reports, 1967-1973 (Box 38, Folder 11-12)
  - Taxation Study Committee Report and Clippings, 1916-1918 (Box 38, Folder 13-14)
  - Taxation and the Liberty Amendment Committee, 1966-1970 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Taxation Clippings, 1967-1973 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Tax Reform Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 38, Folder 17-18)
  - Tax Reports, 1969-1974 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Tax Tables, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Ten Point Program to Modernize Pittsburgh Government, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Welfare Correspondence and Bulletins, 1967-1971 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Welfare and Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission Annual Reports, 1969-72 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Welfare and Urban Redevelopment Authority, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Welfare Publications, 1970, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Workhouse of Allegheny County, 1968-1970 (Box 38, Folder 26)
- Transit, 1905-1974; IX.
  Since the early 1900s, Pittsburgh had faced the problem of transporting people to Downtown from the suburbs and throughout Downtown once they had arrived; however, it became an important and highly debated issue as the 1950s began. There were several different types of transit that were considered for the city such as monorails, buses, and trains. The Civic Club took the time to study each proposal and report on its advantages and disadvantages. The results of these studies were printed in the newspapers, usually the Pittsburgh Press and Post-Gazette, so that the entire city might decide which proposal was right for Pittsburgh. By the time the Civic Club dissolved in 1974, the question of mass transit was still being debated.
  Included are news clippings, correspondence, reports, articles, proposed legislation regarding transit, and plans to widen various tunnels for bus use. The Seven City Report outlines seven North American cities' transit systems in an effort for the Allegheny County Port Authority to construct a reasonable budget for their own system.
  - Traffic, Transit and Port Authority, 1955-1973 (Box 38, Folder 27-38)
  - Traffic, Transit and Port Authority, 1955-1973 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Second and Third Annual Report of Transit Commissioner, 1918-1919 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Transportation Committee Minutes and Report, 1953-1958 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Second Class County Transportation Authority Act, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - "A Plan to Move People by Improved Transit Operation on Existing Streets", 1954 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Research Material on Mass Transit in Pittsburgh, 1955, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Highway Study in Allegheny County, 1957 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Supplemental Report and Recommendations, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Reports and Articles Regarding Mass Transit, 1967-1970 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - The Architectural Forum Special Edition on Mass Transit, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Articles Regarding Transit, 1969-1973 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Articles Regarding Pittsburgh Transit, 1969-1971 (Box 39, Folder 12)